大家注意了
Okay, guys, listen,
明天是艾蜜莉再婚的日子
don't forget that tomorrow is the day that Emily gets married again,
我们要尽全力转移罗斯的注意力
so whatever we do, just try to really keep Ross's mind off of it.
对  好主意
Oh, yeah, good idea.
你怎么了
Hey man, what's up?
正在想艾蜜莉明天结婚的事
Oh, eh, just thinking about Emily getting married tomorrow.
罗斯  你看
Ooh, Ross, look! Look!
看什么  在哪里
What? Where?
就在那儿啊  快看
Right over there! Right there! Look-look-look!
你要我看什么
What am I looking at?
谁来帮帮我啊
Somebody help me out here!
你们好
How are you?
莫妮卡  抱歉我昨晚没过去
Monica, I'm sorry I didn't come by last night.
我跟盖瑞出去了  我们开警车巡逻
I was out with Gary; he let me ride around with him in his cop car.
我们还阻止了一起犯罪
We saw and prevented crimes.
-你可以一起去巡逻吗  -是的
- You got to go on a ride along?! - Uh-huh!
我也要一起去巡逻
I want to go on a ride along!
我也是
Me too!
好啊
Okay!
我也要
Yeah, yeah! Me too!
你真的要吗
Really?! You?
是啊
Yeah.
有点危险哦
Well, it's kinda dangerous.
我喜欢危险
Well, I like danger.
好  你们今天晚上有空吗
Okay, you guys free tonight?
有
Yeah!!
今晚  你刚才没说是在晚上
Tonight? You-you didn't say it was going to be at nighttime.
真高兴你回家了
Oh, I'm so glad you're home,
今晚总算能整理这些照片了
I thought tonight we could finally organize these photos!
谢天谢地  终于要整理了
Ohh, thank God! Finally!
我已经把照片分门别类了
Okay, I've broken them down into categories.
有假日类  生日类和偷拍类
Okay, we have uh, we got holidays, birthdays, candids, y'know...
我已经依照主题做好了交叉搜寻
And then what I've done is I've cross-referenced them by subject.
比如说你要找  生日和狗
Right? So if you're looking up, oh let's say birthdays and dogs,
就会找到152号照片  看
you get Photo 152. See?
是我和拉普  我真怀念那条狗
Ohh, it's me and La Poo! Wow! I miss that dog.
你也能在狗和死亡条目中  找到拉普
You can also find him under umm, dog and dead.
太好了  多谢
Great! Thanks!
把那箱照片递给我  那是最后一箱
All right, hand me that other box of photos; that's the very last one.
好
Okay.
糟糕  抱歉
Oops. Sorry!
幸好你有写上号码  对吧
Well, good thing you number all of them, huh?
还没  152号照片是范例
I hadn't! Photo 152 was a prototype.
亲爱的  别难过  没事的
Ohhhh. Honey, honey, honey, it's okay, it's okay honey.
我帮你弄杯酒  玛格丽特鸡尾酒好吗
I'm gonna fix you a drink, huh? Maybe a margarita?
搅拌机在罗斯那里  一切都毁了
Ross has the blender! Ugh, everything's just falling apart!
亲爱的  不碍事  我去罗斯家拿搅拌机
No honey, it's okay! Listen, I'll got to Ross's and get the blender,
你先准备玛格丽特鸡尾酒的材料
you get all the margarita stuff ready.
好吧  他家钥匙放在抽屉里
All right, he's keys are in the drawer.
我还需要一些现金
Y'know what? I also need some cash.
你要我去自动取款机取吗
Okay, you want me to stop at the ATM?
不用  在罗斯家看到有就拿吧
Nah, while you're at Ross's if you see any lying around...
什么
What?!
什么  我不做那种事的
What?! I-I-I don't, I don't do that!
你逼问那家伙的方式真是太酷了
That was so cool man, the way you leaned on that guy.
天色越来越黑了
It is starting to get dark out there.
他什么都招了  他对你毫不保留
He told you everything! I mean you totally cracked him!
对  他是受害者
Yeah well, being that he was the victim,
他们通常都很多话
they're usually pretty talkative.
好  正式进入夜晚了
Okay.  But it is officially nighttime.
盖瑞  要我帮你拿红灯吗
Oh hey, Gary, want me to grab the berry for ya?
这叫做警灯
It's called the cherry.
叫...  钱德勒
It's the-Chandler!!
买到了
Okay, I got it!
这家店做的三明治世界第一
This place makes the best sandwich in the world!
乔伊  里头有肉丸吗
Hey Joe does it have meatballs on it?
没错
Oh-ho, yeah!
有溶化的芝士和大蒜番茄酱吗
Does it have melted cheese and marinara sauce?
有
Yep!
那就不能在我的车上吃
Yeah, you can't eat that in my car.
好吧  买这部警车的钱我缴的税也有一份
Yeah okay.  Even though my tax dollars paid for this car.
你缴的税
Your tax dollars?
当我没说
Yeah, okay.
这个三明治还真香
Wow! That sandwich really does smell good.
我有说你可以闻吗
Did I say you could smell it?!
闻个三明治都不行吗
I can't smell your sandwich?
香味就占去了好吃的一半
Half the taste is in the smell!
你把好吃都吸光了
You-you're sucking up all the tastiness!
好吧  还给你
Okay, I'll give them back.
这三明治到底棒在哪里
Look! What is so great about that sandwich?
想想你做爱最爽的一次
Okay, imagine the best sex you've ever had.
好
Okay.
你想的是莫妮卡吗
Are you thinking about Monica?
是啊
Yeah.
是什么感觉
Yeah, what's that like?
拜托不要是真的恐龙
Ohh please don't be from a real dinosaur!
拜托  拜托
Please! Please! Please! Please! Please!
拜托
Please! Please! Please!
墨西哥制造  好耶
Made in Mexico! Yes!!
谁会买这种东西啊
Ugh, who would buy this?!
瑞秋  是我  快接啊
Rach! It's me! Pick up!
什么事
Hey! What's up?!
我做玛格丽特鸡尾酒还缺材料
I need a few more things to make the margaritas.
我要盐  玛格丽特汁  还有龙舌兰酒
Uhh, I need some salt, some margarita mix, and tequila.
我们家里只有冰块吗
So all we have is ice?
看看他有没有冰块
See if he has ice.
好吧
Okay.
你好  罗斯  我是艾蜜莉
Hello Ross? It's Emily.
我知道这很突然
I know this is out of the blue
但我明天就要结婚了
but uh, I'm getting married tomorrow.
或许啦
Well, maybe I am.
我一直在想你
I keep thinking about you
不知道我们太快放弃
and I'm wondering if-if we made a mistake
是不是一个错误
giving up so fast.
你有想我吗
Are you thinking about me?
一定没有  如果有的话
Of course you're not, but if you are,
今晚打给我  好吧  再见
call me tonight. Okay, bye.
下一站是哪里
So where are we going next?
这个目击证人不回我电话
This witness won't return my calls
我们去他家给他来个惊喜
so we're gonna see if we can surprise him coming home.
来个惊喜
Sur-surprise him?
他不会生气吧
We're not, we're not gonna make anybody mad are we?
得了吧你
Come on man!
那你会在那贱人的律师出现前
Listen so uh, are you gonna squeeze the perps shoes
先从他身上挤点情报吗
a little bit before he lawyers up?
是证人不是贱人  而且没有人会那样说话
It's a witness not a perp. And no one talks like that!
是啊  没人会那样说话
Yeah, no one talks like that!
难不成你是警察
Oh what? Like your Mr. Cop!
我比你们两个更像警察
Hey, I'm more cop than you two!
这是什么道理
How do you figure that?
醒醒吧  我坐在前座
Hello! I'm in the front seat, okay?
我是盖瑞的搭档
I'm Gary's partner!
你说搭档的时候不像警察
Y'know, when you say partner it doesn't sound cop.
倒像是同志
It sounds gay.
你眼红
Umm, jealous!
麻烦别张扬  我们这是秘密出勤
Hey, do you mind? We're under cover here.
好  没问题
Yeah, no problem.
罗斯
Ross!
抱歉  好了
Sorry! Sorry! Oh, there!
盖瑞  猜我是谁  打电话回家
Hey Gary, who am I? Phone home!
罗斯警官被打入后座  和访客一起了
Look at Officer Ross riding back here with the visitors.
是啊  怎么一回事呢  塞尔皮科警官
Yeah, what's up with that Serpico?
你有想我吗
Are you thinking about me?
一定没有  如果有的话
Of course you're not, but if you are,
今晚打给我  好吧  再见
call me tonight. Okay, bye.
不妙
Nooo!
我知道
I know!
幸好你在这里  我们得把这段留言删掉
Well thank God you were here! I mean, we have to erase that!
什么  我们不能那样
What?! We can't do that!
非这样不可  万一罗斯听到了
We have too! I mean what if Ross's hears that
回电给她  他们又复合了怎么办
and then calls her back and then they get back together?
你希望那样吗
Is that what you want?
罗斯跟那个控制欲超强
Ross back with that controlling,
神经质的疯子艾蜜莉复合
neurotic, crazy Emily?
那个不让罗斯见你的艾蜜莉
The Emily that wouldn't let him see you?
不行  万万不可
Noo! Oh no! No! God no!
罗斯绝对不能和她复合
He should not get back together with her.
你知我知  就连罗斯都知道
I know that! You know that! Even Ross knows that!
但我们还是没权力擅自删掉罗斯的留言
But that still doesn't give us the right to erase his message!
我是他的妹妹  我爱他
I'm his sister, okay? I love him!
不想看他受到伤害
I don't want to see him get hurt!
拜托  我这样还没有权控制...
Come on! Doesn't that give me the right to control him-
帮助他吗
help him?
我觉得需要帮助的不是他
I don't think he's the one who needs help.
艾蜜莉情绪不稳定
No, look, she's obviously unstable, okay?
她竟然想在结婚当天落跑
I mean she's thinking about running out on her wedding day.
好啦  但你看看她让罗斯陷入了什么处境
Okay, fine! But I mean, look at the position she's putting him in!
你要罗斯怎么办
What's he gonna do?
难不成在艾蜜莉结婚当天
Ross is gonna run over there on the wedding day
跑去破坏婚礼  谁做得出那种事
and break up the marriage?! I mean, who would do that?!
好啦  不过这是两码子事
Okay, fine, all right, but that's y'know, it's different!
虽然两件事的主角都是一样的
Although it did involve a lot of the same people.
艾蜜莉显然想用变态的笑话
Y'know what, this is obviously some kind of twisted joke
来恶整罗斯
she's trying to play on him.
够了  你疯了
Okay, you are crazy!
她听起来真的很沮丧  你听听
I'm sorry, but she sounded generally upset! I mean, listen!
您的留言已经删除
Your messages have been erased.
不会吧
Noooooooo!
我们很安全  对吧
Okay, y'know, we-we're safe right?
不可能会有厄运降临
I mean nothing bad can go down!
对  不过我倒想起来了  签一下这个
No. But that reminds me,  sign this.
这是什么
What is it?
没什么  只是断腿或脑袋开花
Oh it's nothing, it just says that you can't sue the city
也不能告到市政府头上
if you scrap your knee or y'know, get your head blown off.
快点哦  我要签
Oh, hurry up. I want to sign that.
好了  他来了
Okay, here he comes.
他在干嘛  搞什么鬼
What is he doing? What the hell is he doing?!
什么  怎么了
What? What? What? What is it?
没事吧
Is everything okay?
发生什么事了
What's going on?
他看到我们了  别动  不要看他
Okay, he sees us. Now don't move. Don't look at him.
没事的  只是车子逆火
Hey, it's okay. It was just a car backfire.
瞧啊  你想用身体掩护朋友
Hey, look at that! You tried to save your buddy.
看到没有  看到他的表现了吗
You see that? You see what he did?
你没事吧
You okay man?
乔伊  谢了
Thank Joey!
喂
Uh, Hello!!
嗨
Hi.
好了  我们该走了
All right, I guess we should go.
等等
No, wait. Wait.
是哦
Oh yeah right!
不是啦  莫妮卡  我们得补救这个
No, Monica! Monica! We have to fix this!
我们无能为力啊  你已经把留言删掉了
There's nothing we can do. You erased the message!
我可以老实跟他说啊
I could tell him about it.
如果你想要这么明理的话
Well, if you're gonna be totally rational about this,
我也争不过你
I can't argue with you! All right?
好啦  你想告诉他就说吧
Fine, if you wanna tell him, tell him.
我不想介入
I just don't want to be a part of it.
或许又是艾蜜莉打来  说同样的话
Oh, maybe that's Emily calling back to leave the exact same message.
罗斯  是你啊
Hey Ross! It's you!
我只是要你记住这种感觉
I just want you to remember this feeling.
活着是一种幸运
You are lucky to be alive!
所以每一天都要活得精彩
So live everyday to the fullest.
珍爱自己  好吗
Love yourself, okay?
别忘了买邮票  再见
Okay. Oh, and also get stamps. Bye!
只要把这留言放给艾蜜莉听
Wow! Play that message for Emily
-所有的问题都解决了  -可不是
-and this whole problem goes away! - Right?
有人想见见英雄吗
Hey, anybody want to meet a hero?
约翰·葛林来了吗(著名宇航员)
John Glenn is here?!
不  是乔伊
No, Joey!
菲比  今晚真是太不可思议了
Pheebs, we had the most incredible night!
我们在警车里
Okay, so, we're in the car...
慢着
Wait! Hold on!
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi! - Hi!
好  继续说
Okay, go ahead.
我们在警车里
Okay, okay, so we're in the car. Right?
突然砰一声  有人开枪
And bang! A shot was fired.
乔伊完全不顾自己的安危
And Joey with no regard for his own safety
扑到我身上保护我
throws himself on me!
天啊  乔伊
My God, Joey!
那是汽车逆火放屁的声音
It was a car backfire!
对  但是当时他并不知道
Yeah, but-but he didn't know that!
对  我不知道
Yeah, I didn't know that.
那很有可能会是子弹的
And it could've just as easily have been a bullet.
乔伊  你有没有想过要当警察
Hey Joe, you ever think about joining the force?
警界很需要你这种人
We could use a guy like you.
听到巨响就吓得跳起来
Who jumps at loud noises!
哇  我今晚有可能丧命的
Wow! I could've died tonight.
对  如果那部放屁的车把你碾过去的话
Yeah! If the car that backfired had run over you!
我先回家去了  省得罗斯
Y'know what, I'm gonna go home before Ross starts rambling
大谈人生新发现
about his newfound respect for life.
我的人生的确有了新发现
I do have a newfound respect for life.
我的天
Oh my God!
亲爱的  你要吃晚餐吗
Sweetheart, you wanna get some dinner?
好啊  当然
Yeah! Sure! Yep!
你知道吗
Oh, y'know what?
如果现在听到枪声  我一定会扑到你身上
If I heard a shot right now, I'd throw my body on you.
是吗
Oh yeah?
那我们或许应该去治安不好的街区散步
Well maybe you and I should take a walk through a bad neighborhood.
-好的  -好
- Okay! - All right.
再见
Bye!
罗斯  你别再闹了
Cut it out Ross!
我不想在同一天里  救完你又痛扁你一顿
I hate to have to save your life and kick your ass in the same day!
兄弟  你刚才怎么先闪了
Dude! How come you took off?
我只是去散步
Oh, I just went for a walk,
在客厅里绕来绕去
around the living room. Whatever...
有什么不对吗
Is something wrong?
没有  我只是累了
No. No I'm just tired.
走路走累了
Y'know, from-from the walk.
好吧
Okay.
你扑上去救罗斯  罗斯
You dove in front of Ross! Ross!
原来是这么一回事
That's what this is about!
天啊  你恨罗斯
Oh my God, you hate Ross!
我没有恨罗斯
I do not hate Ross!
你当然有  我救了他
Of course you do! I saved him!
你生我的气  这下全都说得通了
You're mad at me! It all adds up!
你想铲除罗斯
You want Ross out of the picture.
铲除什么
What picture?
不知道  但是你说的话很不中听
I don't know, but I don't like what I'm hearing!
我很高兴你在汽车放屁事件中  救了罗斯
Look I'm very glad that you saved Ross from the car backfire,
但那如果真的是子弹怎么办
but it could've been a bullet and you y'know,
你竟然救他不救我
you didn't try to save me!
原来你在气这个
Ohh, you're upset
你以为我觉得罗斯比你重要
because you think I chose Ross over you!
不是这样的  我知道你能照顾自己
No! I...knew...you could take care of yourself.
罗斯需要别人照顾  他不像你我见过大场面
Y'know, I mean Ross, he need help. He's not street like us!
归根结底  你宁愿冒死救罗斯
When it comes down to it, you would risk your life for Ross
也不来救我  这才是重点
before you would for me. That's the bottom line.
不完全是这样  听我说
Well, no, not exactly! All right, look, I,
我那不是要救罗斯  明白吗
I wasn't trying to save Ross. Okay?
我的三明治在罗斯旁边
My sandwich was next to Ross.
懂了吗
All right?
我是要救我的三明治
I was, I was trying to save my sandwich.
怕它被枪打到
From a bullet!
我知道这说来没啥道理
I know it doesn't make much sense...
岂止没啥道理
Much sense?!
钱德勒  那是本能反应
Look Chandler, it was instinct!
当时就扑过去了
Okay? I just went for it!
所以你冒死去救三明治
So you risked your life, for a sandwich!
我知道这听起来很夸张  钱德勒
I know it sounds crazy, but Chandler
但这可是世界上最棒的三明治
this is  the greatest sandwich in the world!
所以你并不觉得罗斯比我重要
So you didn't uh, choose Ross before me.
是啊  我绝对不会那样
No! I would never do that!
你就像是我的亲兄弟
You-you're like my brother!
真的
Really?!
对  事实上
Yeah! In fact,
为了证明你对我来说有多重要
to prove how much you mean to me,
给你
here.
谢了
Thanks.
小心点  这不是热狗
No, eh, oh-oi, easy, it's not a hot dog!
是不是很好吃
How good is that?
看吧
See?
慢着  兄弟  你在干嘛
Oh-whoa-hey, dude, what are you doing?!
你不是要证明我对你来说很重要吗
I thought you were showing me how much you mean to me.
是啊  用一口来证明  有没搞错
Yeah. With a bite!  Gee-e-e-eez!
瑞秋  你在这里干嘛
Rach, what uh, what are you doing here?
知道吗  你动不动就往我们公寓跑
Hey! Y'know what? You are in our apartment all the time! Okay?
我这只是小巫见大巫而已
This is, this is just a drop in the bucket mister!
没关系啦  重点是你来了
Y'know, it-it doesn't matter. The important thing is that you're here.
你是我朋友  而你来到了这里
You're my friend, and you're here. Oh!
我有一点点害怕  罗斯  你是怎么了
Okay, just a little scared. What's going on Ross?
今晚发生了最不寻常的事
The most amazing thing happened tonight.
我还以为自己要去见阎王了
I thought my number was up.
我体验了真正的濒死经历
I had an actual near death experience!
什么  怎么回事
What?! What? What happened?!
我们不是跟盖瑞一起开车巡逻吗
Okay, okay, we were on the ride along with Gary, right?
有人冲我开枪
And somebody took a shot at me!
真的吗
Really?!
不是  是车子逆火  但是
No, a car backfired, but
我当时以为有人冲我开枪
I thought somebody was taking a shot at me.
瑞秋  我是劫后余生啊
And Rach, I...I survived!
我的人生拥有了全新视野
And I was filled with this-this great respect for life.
我要真切体验每一刻
Y'know? I-I want to experience every moment.
我要把握每一个机会
I want to seize every opportunity.
现在一切都变得好清晰
I-I am seeing everything so-so clearly now.
就因为汽车逆火吗
Because a car backfired?
好吧  你来这里干嘛
Okay, why are you here?
我不知道这算不算你所谓的"把握今朝"
Well, I-I-I don't know how this fits into your whole "seizing" thing
不过艾蜜莉今天打了电话给你
but um, Emily called you today.
你跟她说了话
You talked to her?
没有  她留言了
No, she left a message.
不过留言被删掉了
But it-it kinda got erased.
你的答录机有问题
There's just something wrong with your machine.
那她说了什么
Well, okay, what-what did she say?
说什么对结婚的事有点迟疑
Well, uh something about having second thoughts about the wedding
说你们分手是个错误
and did you guys make a mistake breaking up
她要你回电
and uh, she wants you to call her.
哇
Wow!
我跟你说这件事很对吧
Now, that-that was a good thing that I told you, right?
是啊  当然是这样
Huh? Yeah! Yes, of course!
谢谢你  因为...  抱歉没事了
Okay. Thank you! Thank you! Because-I'm sorry, all right.
我要去跟莫妮卡说  我这样做是对的
I'm gonna go tell Monica that I was right.
你知道吗  她不希望我...  算了
Because y'know what? She didn't want me-not important.
重点是我是对的  你自己决定
The point is, I was right. Your decision.
我是对的  你自己决定
Okay? I was right. Your decision.
对  我想我应该回电给艾蜜莉
Right. I guess, I guess I should call Emily.
不对  你的决定不对
Okay, no, that's not the right decision.
不对  罗斯  你清醒一点
That's not, that's not right, no Ross-Ross, come on!
我的意思是  那个女人把你给整惨了
I mean, that woman made you miserable!
罗斯  你真的还想自找麻烦吗
Okay, Ross, do you really want to get back into that?
如果她是在昨天打来的
Okay, look, yesterday I would've even
我压根不会想回电
considered  calling her back,
我体验濒死经历的当天
but my ex-wife calls on the same day
我的前妻正好打电话来
I have a near death experience.
这一定有所含义
I mean, that-that has got to mean something!
罗斯  那不是濒死经历
Ugh, Ross! That was not a near death experience!
就连经历都谈不上
That was barely an experience!
当时你并不在场
You weren't there!
或许这就是我应该把握的事
Okay, maybe this is something that I-I'm supposed to seize! Y'know?
好吧  你知道吗
Okay, y'know what?
或许这无关把握或是不把握
Maybe, this is not about seizing stuff.
或许这是关于逃避
Maybe this is about escaping stuff.
就拿今天来说
I mean, look-look today
你逃过了  死亡
you escaped death,
或许这正是给你逃避的机会
y'know? And maybe this is a chance for you to escape
不去和艾蜜莉复合
getting back together with Emily?
这还蛮有道理的
That does make sense.
因为我要把握住这个机会
Because I do wanna seize some opportunity,
不和她见面或联络
but I-I really don't wanna see or talk to her.
这不就结了
Well, there you go!
或许今天就是
Yeah. Maybe today is just,
"千钧一发"日(字面意是差点打电话)
close call day.
瑞秋  谢了
Hey, thanks Rach.
亲爱的  甭客气
Ohh, honey no problem.
等等  留言灯在闪
Okay. Oh wait-wait-wait! The message is blinking.
或许留言没被删掉
Maybe you didn't erase it.
罗斯  是你啊
"Hey Ross, it's you!"
这是旧的留言  没什么好听的
Oh yeah, no that's-that's an old message, nobody needs to hear that.
莫妮卡有来过吗
Hey umm, was-was Monica here?
有啊
Yeah.
叫她把我的钱还来
Yeah, I want my money back.
是要用来买邮票的吧
Yeah, uh you-you probably need that for stamps, right?
菲比  盖瑞有真的中枪过吗
Hey Pheebs, has Gary ever been shot at for real?
有  一次  小小的一次
Yes. Once. Yeah, a little.
算是他自己打的
He kinda did it to himself.
这故事没什么好讲的
It's not really a good story.
不知道我置身枪战会怎样
I wonder how I would react under fire, y'know?
不是汽车逆火  是枪林弹雨
And not backfire but-but heavy fire,
好比我在战场上之类的
like I was in a war or something.
我去打仗一定很厉害
Man, I would be great in a war!
一定会是很棒的军事领袖
I mean, I really, I think I would make a fantastic military leader.
跟你们这些人比起来
I mean I know I would make General
我一定会最先当上将军
before any of you guys.
在你被自己的部下枪杀前还是之后
Before or after you were shot by your own troops?
我知道乔伊会在哪里
I know where Joey would be.
他一定会在散兵坑里保护大家
He would be down in the foxhole protecting all of us.
对  如果那个散兵坑是用三明治围起来的话
Yes, if the foxhole was lined with sandwiches.
没错  英雄三明治
Yeah, hero sandwiches.
你们知道我主张和平
Well you all know that I'm a pacifist
我对战争没什么兴趣
so I'm not interested in war in any way.
不过
But y'know what?
等到革命来临的那一天
When the revolution comes,
我一定会把你们消灭光
I will have to destroy you all.
乔伊  你除外
Not you Joey.